太空堡垒卡拉狄加 【 前情提要 】
STARBUCK: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
这颗星球上的海藻足够整个舰队享用
GAETA: There's enough algae on this planet to feed the entire fleet,
不过该星系中的一颗恒星极其不稳定
but the star in the system is highly unstable.
说出来您也许不信 它处于变成超新星的边缘
If you can believe it, on the verge of going supernova.
我们刚发现四艘赛昂基地之星高速袭来
TIGH: We just picked up four baseships inbound at high speed.
赛昂人发现
ADAMA: It's just a matter of time
我们来此的意图只是时间问题
until the Cylons find out what we're up to on this planet.
星芭坠机了
DUALLA: Starbuck has gone down!
我要去救我的妻子!
I am going after my wife!
不行 山姆    我用不着让你同意
I can't let you do that, Sam. I am not asking you for permission.
马赛厄斯中士
Sergeant Mathias.
如果我告诉你 你的女儿还尚在人间呢
BOOMER: What if I told you that your daughter was still alive?
你说谎    她现在就在我们的基地之星上
I'd say you were lying. She's on our baseship right now.
她病了 而我们不知道是何原因
She's ill, and we don't know why.
我说不清自己怎么找到这个地方的
TYROL: I don't even know how I found this place.
我就是想向前走 然后突然就到了这里
I just got this urge to start walking, and then suddenly here it is.
依经文上所述 这间神庙是
The scriptures say that this Temple is the final resting place
朱庇特之眼的最终所在地
of the Eye of Jupiter.
到底是什么意思?
What exactly are we talking about?
那是第13部落所留下的标记
It's a marker that was left behind by the Thirteenth Tribe.
它可以指明到达地球的道路
It's supposed to point the way to Earth.
我们要"朱庇特之眼"
We want the Eye of Jupiter.
胆敢攻击这艘战舰或那颗星球上我的手下
Make any attempt to attack this ship or the people on the planet's surface,
我就把全部的核弹发射出去
I'll launch every nuke I've got.
少校 在轮机长找到"朱庇特之眼"以前
ADAMA: Major, you've got to hold off the Cylons
你一定要拖住赛昂人
until Chief finds the Eye of Jupiter.
如果他们要进入神庙 你的命令就是摧毁它
If it looks like they're gonna get into the Temple, your order is to blow it.
我们必须去那颗星球
We have to go down to the planet.
我就快看到最后五个赛昂人的样子了
I am so close to seeing the faces of the last five Cylons.
只有进入神庙的人 才能看到"终极五人"
HYBRID: The Final Five, revealed only to those who enter the Temple.
只有被神选中的人才能看到 被神选中的人才能看到
Only to the Chosen One... The Chosen One...
我们刚发现六艘重型突袭机向那颗星球飞去
We just picked up six Heavy Raiders heading down toward the planet.
地面核打击导弹预备
Order nuclear ground-strike missiles.
我不会让赛昂人拿到"朱庇特之眼"
I'm not gonna let the Cylons get their hands on the Eye.
我们是要牺牲李吗?
ROSLIN: Are we prepared to sacrifice Lee?
上将  导弹已装载完毕
Missiles are loaded, Admiral.
批准使用核武器
Release of nuclear weapons is now authorized.
盖塔先生
Mr. Gaeta.
解除四到十号管道的核弹发射保险
Disable launch and warhead safeties on tubes 4 through 10.
保险已解除 核弹待命
Safeties disabled. Warheads are armed.
副官
XO,
请输入你的发射码
please input your firing code.
这些核弹将把神庙周围方圆20里范围夷为平地
These nukes will obliterate anything or anyone within 20 clicks of the Temple.
我知道
ADAMA: I know.
他真要动手了 立即召回突袭机
LEOBEN: He's gonna do it. Recall the Raiders immediately.
我们赞成 让他们回来
We agree. Bring them back.
我们赞成 到了这个地步
We agree. After all this time,
我们无法承担失去这一切的后果
we can't afford to lose everything.
我们同意 让他们回来
We agree. Bring them back.
如果卡拉死了 我对天发誓 我会亲自要了你的命
If Kara dies out there, I swear to Gods, I will kill you myself.
如果她真的死了 悉听尊便
If she dies out there, I'll let you.
那我们现在要做什么?  拿把枪跟着我?
So, what are we gonna do now, follow me around with a gun?
就因为只有这样 才能阻止我去救卡拉?
Because that is the only way that I am not going after Kara.
列兵塞克斯    在  长官
Private Sykes. Sir?
联系杜亚拉中尉
Get Lieutenant Dualla on the line.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
我在
I'm here.
发现星芭的所在地了吗?
APOLLO: Do you have eyeballs on Starbuck's position?
没有 我们没发现星芭的猛禽机
Negative. We have no visual on her Raptor,
不过可以看到坠机点升起的黑烟
but I can see smoke from the crash site.
她在几里外的山后坠毁的
She went down behind a hill a couple clicks away.
能够到达她的猛禽机那里吗?
Can you get to the Raptor?
不知道 很远  掩体很少
I don't know. It's pretty far away. There's minimal cover.
可行吗?
Is it doable?
不知道
I don't know.
钥匙
Key.
待命
Standing by.
发射次序设为自动
Launch sequence set to auto.
他们同我们一样 也想取得找到地球的钥匙
D'ANNA: They want the key to finding Earth as much as we do.
他不会一手毁掉它的
He won't just destroy it.
我们已讨论过了 已做出了决定
We spoke, and the decision's been made.
按我口令发射
Fire on my mark.
长官  突袭机返回了
Sir, the Raiders are turning back.
并非全部 更正 五架突袭机返回了
Not all of them. Correction. Five have turned back.
仍有一架向那颗星球飞去
One is still en route back to the planet.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
他不会因为一艘飞船而发射核弹的
He won't launch against just one ship.
不会的    问题不在这里
He won't. That's not the issue.
我们已做出了决定 戴・安娜必须撤回
We made a decision. D'Anna has to turn back.
不
No.
通知戴・安娜和波塔尔
CAPRICA SIX: Call D'Anna and Baltar.
让他们立即撤回    不
Turn them around now. D'ANNA: No!
"不"是什么意思?
What do you mean, no?
我们必须这么做
This is something that we have to do.
他不会为一艘飞船而发射核弹的 你们看着吧
He won't launch over one ship. You'll see.
你想让我...
You want me...
你想让我营救瑟瑞丝上尉?
You want me to rescue Captain Thrace?
设法营救
Attempt the rescue.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
狐火通话完毕
Foxfire One out.
走吧
We go.
上将  武器仍在待命
TIGH: Weapons are still hot, Admiral.
收回导弹  关闭发射口
Safe all missiles. Close outer doors.
看到了吗?
There. You see?
他绝不会因小失大
Never over just one ship.
这可不是一个好兆头  朋友们
That is not a good sign, my friends.
她违抗我们  违抗组织
She defied us, defied the group.
我们的问题已不是"朱庇特之眼"了  而是她
LEOBEN: It's not about the Eye of Jupiter. It's about her.
她仿佛与我们形同陌路了一样
It's like we don't even know them anymore.
我们必须要对此采取一些措施
We may have to do something about this.
迟早都要采取一些措施
We may have to do it sooner than later.
赫拉还活着 我是她的母亲  我要去找她
Hera's alive. I'm her mother, and I'm going to get her.
莎伦  宝贝 听我说
Sharon, baby, listen to me, okay?
我们可以驾驶猛禽机 单独去赛昂母舰
We can take a Raptor. We can fly to the baseship ourselves.
我不在乎了
I don't... I don't care anymore.
行不通
We can't.
那我们再想办法 会有办法的
We'll find another way. We will.
没其他的路可走了
There is no other way.
别让我这么做  莎伦
Don't ask me to do this, Sharon.
听我说
Listen to me.
一直以来 你都是铮铮硬汉
You have always been the strong one.
当所有人都不相信我们能长相厮守的时候 你相信
You believed in us when no one else would.
我求你了
I'm begging you to do this.
鼓起勇气 为了我们两个人  好吗?
Find the courage to do this for both of us, okay?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
到外面等    是  长官
Wait outside. Yes, sir.
莎伦正下载到
ROSLIN: Sharon's downloading into another body
赛昂母舰上的一副新躯体里吧?
aboard a Cylon ship right now, isn't she?
她求我的
She begged me.
是她求我那么做的
She begged me to do it.
天啊  如果你...
Gods, if you'd...
当时看到她的那双眼睛--        她持有关于…
Seen the look in her eyes when I... She has important information
我们防御体系的重要情报 密码  程序
on our defenses. Codes, procedures,
以及那颗星球上的战术布局
the tactical situation down on the planet's surface.
这些赛昂人也都得到了
The Cylons have access to all of that as well.
她不会背叛我们
She won't betray us.
这您清楚
You know that.
所以您才给她制服的
It's why you gave her the uniform.
她可能身不由己 这你考虑过吗?
She may not have a choice. Did you consider that?
她说过她会反抗 不会泄露军情
She says she could resist, that she wouldn't let it happen.
她找到赫拉后
She'll get Hera,
就会回来
and she'll come back.
好个信任度的提升  上尉
That's quite a leap of faith you've made, there, Captain.
如果只有你的家庭承担风险 我会赞扬你的勇敢
And if it involved your family only, I'd say it was brave.
但你是在以整个舰队冒险 你知道吗?
But you've put the entire fleet in jeopardy, are you aware of that?
如果不是你先说谎...
If you hadn't lied
然后偷走我们的孩子...
and stolen our baby in the first place,
我们也就不至于到此地步
we wouldn't be here at all.
让大家落到此种境遇 我的确负有责任
I've certainly played my part in bringing us to this moment.
我会承担诸多的责难与过失
And there's plenty of blame to throw around, and I accept it.
现在我们所有人的性命 都掌握在莎伦・阿格森的手中
And now all of our lives are in the hands of Sharon Agathon.
我们只能希望你的妻子
All we can do is hope that your wife is worthy
不会辜负你对她无条件的信任
of the unconditional trust you place in her, Captain.
以及您对她的信任  上将
And you as well, Admiral.
出了什么事?
Can you tell me what happened?
他们不让我见我的女儿
They wouldn't let me see my daughter,
所以我丈夫杀了我
so my husband shot me.
只能如此
It was the only way.
一切都已经过去了
Well, it's over now.
重要的是你在这里
The important thing is that you're here.
我女儿怎么样了?
How's my daughter?
病情加重了
She's getting worse.
我要去见她
I want to see her.
然后呢?
And then what?
他们对我所做的一切...
What they did to me,
偷走我的孩子...
stealing my baby
然后告诉我她已经死了...
and telling me she was dead...
都被你说中了
You proved it.
赫拉在这里是安全的
Hera's safer here,
我也一样
and so am I.
在她坠机之前...
All right, before she went down,
星芭发现 多于15个"整容人"正向我方行进
Starbuck spotted about 15-plus chrome jobs advancing on us from here.
要到我们这里 这条峡谷是"烤面包机"们的必经之路
To get to us, the toasters have to come through this canyon.
这里是天然的阻塞点
This is a natural choke point.
我们就在这里埋伏它们
That's where we'll ambush them,
打游击战
guerilla style.
我们的任务是把守这里的神庙
Our mission is to hold the Temple here.
如果任务失败 我们就炸毁它
If we fail, we blow it up.
然后撤退到这些会合点
We fall back to these rendezvous points.
然后进山  等待救援
And then we head into the mountains, and we wait for rescue.
和别处一样 这里也是上西天的好地方
Well, it's a good a place as any to die, I suppose.
怎么样?
What do you think?
散步的好天气
It's a nice day for a walk.
狙击手!
DUALLA: Sniper!
小心点  费希尔
Hey, take it easy, Fischer.
中士?
Sarge?
真伤脑筋  好好想想
This is crazy. Come on, think, think.
加伦  阿达玛少校打来的
Galen, it's Major Adama.
长官
Sir.
轮机长  我们就位了
APOLLO: Chief, we're in position.
找到"朱庇特之眼"了吗?
Any luck finding the Eye of Jupiter?
没有  少校 我还需要时间
No, Major. I need more time.
找吧  赛昂人行动了
Get on it. The Cylons are on the move.
我们尽量拖延它们
We'll hold them off as long as we can.
阿波罗通话完毕
Apollo out.
各位听好 收拾好装备  准备撤退
All right, listen up! Pack your gear, get ready to move!
明白    好的
MAN 1: I've got this. WOMAN: All right.
轮机长 我们撤吧
MAN 2: Hey, Chief, let's get out of here.
近在咫尺 我知道
It's so close. I know.
你所有问题的答案就在下面的神庙中
The answers to all your questions are down there in that temple.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我有些担心  盖尤斯
I'm worried, Gaius.
我们一直以来就在等待这个时刻
This is what we've been waiting for.
你是神所选派的
You are the anointed one.
你是去观看"终极五人"的人选
Chosen by God to look on the faces of the Final Five Cylons.
一切都是上苍注定的
It's already written.
你会成功的
You will succeed.
我怕的就是这事
That's what I'm afraid of.
看到神的面孔 必会走向疯狂
To know the face of God is to know madness.
"混合体"所看到的空间是生死之间
The Hybrid has looked into the space between life and death,
她可以看到我们无法察觉到的事情
and she's seen things that we cannot conceive of,
而结果却落得疯疯癫癫的下场
but she's been driven mad as a result.
相信神
Have faith in God.
把你的性命交给他
Put your life in his hands.
他会指引你去完成你的宿命
He will guide you to your destiny.
我很感激你...
I'm grateful to you.
为我所做的一切
For everything.
你们两人的宿命将分道扬镳 盖尤斯
Her destiny will part company from yours, Gaius.
她不是被神所选中的 而你是
She's not the Chosen One. You are.
是  我知道
Yes, I know.
我知道
I know.
准备?    拿到了
Ready? I got it.
我们准备好了 现在就守株待兔了
APOLLO: Okay, we're set. And now we wait.
如果少校的如意算盘落空了怎么办?
What happens if the Cylons don't dance to the Major's tune?
如果我们被逼得分开了怎么办?
What happens is we get splattered all over these rocks.
闭嘴  这是他的战术 不是我们的
Shut up. This is his game, not ours.
我们按他说的去做 也许可以脱身
We just do what we're told, and maybe we get out of here.
这些民兵真能阻止它们吗?
You really think these civvies can stop them?
我们还在逃命的时候 他们在卡布里卡上就做到了
Well, they stopped plenty of them on Caprica while we were running for our lives.
三位"破铜烂铁" 已进入我们的杀伤区了
Okay, three clankers just entered our kill zone.
肯定是它们的侦察兵
Gotta be their recon element.
塞克斯 给他们信号
Sykes, give them the signal.
好  大显身手的时候到了
All right, showtime, showtime.
它们向我们这边来了
All right, they're headed our way.
等到它们都进来以后再引爆
Don't detonate till they're all the way in.
等待
Wait for it.
来吧  混蛋  来啊
Come on, you sons of bitches. Come on.
快  快
Now, now, now, now.
小心!
Look out!
有人负伤!
Man down!
停火!  它们撤退了!
Cease fire! They're pulling back! They're pulling back!
干!
Frak!
天杀的!
Gods damn it!
过来!
APOLLO: Come on!
见鬼
Damn it.
妈的
Frak, frak.
人已经死了 我们得把他拉回来
Okay, this man's dead. We gotta pull him back.
山姆  振作
Sam, pull it together.
我们争取到了一些时间
APOLLO: All right, we bought ourselves a little time,
不过它们会带重兵回来
but they'll be back and with force,
找好掩体
so dig in.
我们要拖住它们 直到轮机长找到"朱庇特之眼"
We'll need to hold them off until Chief finds the Eye.
注意那些山脊地带
And keep your eyes out on those ridges.
有卡拉或小杜的消息吗?
You have any word from Kara or Dee?
没有
No.
星芭?
Starbuck?
星…
Star...
小杜  你怎么那么大声
Dee, why the hell didn't you sing out?
我差点把你干掉
I almost blew you away.
我也很高兴见到你
Glad to see you, too.
好  好
Okay, okay.
没关系
It's okay, yeah.
李派你来的?
Lee sent you?
恩
Yep.
我丈夫...
My husband
命令我冒着生命危险来救你
ordered me to risk my life for yours.
我要来救你
That's what I'm gonna do.
要把星芭带回去见阿波罗
I'm gonna bring Starbuck back to Apollo.
她在这里
She's here.
是我啊
It's me.
我是妈妈
It's Mommy. Yes.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我们什么方法都试过了 也不见起色
We tried everything. She didn't respond.
看啊 赫拉认识她
Look at that. Hera knows her.
好神奇 你们俩在生理上毫无二致
That's amazing. You and she are biologically identical.
而赫拉却认出了她的母亲
But Hera recognizes her mother.
这就好  你留着她吧 我可受够了
Well, good, because you can have her. I'm done with her.
这不是你的真心话
You don't mean that.
我知道你还是在乎蒂罗尔和阿达玛的
I know you still care about Tyrol and Adama.
不
No.
那样的日子已经一去不返了
I'm done with that part of my life.
这是我在新卡布里卡上学到的
I learnt that on New Caprica.
人类与赛昂人 命中注定就不该在一起
Humans and Cylons were not meant to be together.
我们就应该各走各的路
We should just go our separate ways.
躺下吧
Wanna lay down?
她的肚子好硬 你们之前注意到了吗?
Her belly's as hard as a rock. Have you noticed that before?
能是什么事?
What do you think that means?
可能是肠阻塞
Blocked intestine, maybe.
我们的医生给她做过体检
Our doctors examined her.
你们的医生从没给幼儿做过体检
Well, your doctors have never examined a child.
要让人类的医生给赫拉看病
Hera needs to be seen by a human doctor.
我得带她回卡拉狄加
I need to take her back to Galactica.
你明知这是不可能的   你也清楚这孩子对我们何等重要
You know that can't happen, what this child means to us.
对每一个赛昂人有多重要
What she means to every living Cylon.
我早该料到 这一切都是她计划好了的
I should have known. She's been planning this all along.
你亲自去摸摸她
Feel her.
没错
She's right.
她的肚子确实很硬
Belly's as hard as a gourd.
如果你不让我带她走 新生代的第一人就会死掉
If you don't let me take her, the first of a new generation will die.
神永远也不会宽恕你
God will never forgive you.
也许还是卡维尔说得对
Maybe Cavil's right.
可能神从一开始 就没想让我们拥有孩子
Maybe God never wanted us to have children in the first place.
或许为了你好 我应该扭断你的小脖子
Maybe it'd be better for you if I just snapped your little neck!
不要
Don't!
求你...
Please.
求你不要杀害我的小女儿
Please don't kill my baby girl.
宝贝
Honey!
我相信这孩子决定着赛昂人的未来
I believe the future of the Cylon rests with this child,
其他人还会来加害她
and the others who are gonna come after her.
我想也是
So do I.
舰上有一艘捕获的猛禽机
There's a captured Raptor aboard.
走吧
Let's go.
我们得送你回卡拉狄加
We've gotta get you back to Galactica.
它们来了
Here they come.
开火!
Open fire!
通知他们把那东西炸了
Tell them to blow the thing!
赛昂人逼近了
The Cylons are closing in!
少校打来的
It's the Major.
蒂罗尔 找到"朱庇特之眼"了吧?
Tyrol. Tell me you've found the Eye of Jupiter.
还没  不过快了
No, but I'm getting close, Major.
我又认出了一些字
I've deciphered some more of the glyphs.
有一处提到"眼睛"
I got a reference to an eye,
还提到了"恒星"  "爆炸"什么的
something about a star, and an explosion of some kind.
长话短说  轮机长
All right, cut to the chase, Chief.
你是否拿到了"朱庇特之眼"?
Do you have the Eye of Jupiter in your hands or not?
没有  少校
No, Major.
它来了
That's it!
开火了
It's hot!
好了  轮机长 听我说  到此结束
All right, Chief, listen to me. That's it!
带你的人去会合点 然后炸毁神庙
Get your people to the rally point and blow the Temple.
重复一遍  炸毁神庙
I repeat, blow the Temple.
是  长官  该死
Yes, sir. Damn it.
撤退!
All right, fall back!
塞克斯 马赛厄斯 撤退!
Sykes, Mathias, fall back!
撤退!  撤退!
Fall back! Fall back!
好了  就这样了 各位  放下手里的活  撤退
All right, that's it, everybody. Drop what you're doing and get out.
拿到了    好 接这个
MAN 1: I've got this. MAN 2: All right, take that one.
你也一样  凯莉
That means you, too, Cally. Come on!
好吧 带上那个绳…
MAN 1: Okay, bring the cord...
把装备丢下!  快走!
TYROL: Leave the gear! Go!
走    拿好了
MAN 2: Go. WOMAN: I've got it.
再给我一点时间就好了    加伦
If I only had a little more time. Galen.
一切都随天意吧 走吧
It's in the hands of the Gods now, okay? Let's go.
我们无能为力了
There's nothing we can do!
船体完好    好
The ship's structurally intact. Okay.
这也就是说我们飞不起来的原因出自遥控自动驾驶仪
That means that the only thing keeping us grounded is a busted fly-by wire.
所以...
So...
你得绕开那捆线  用通讯系统中的数据线形成旁路
You gotta bypass those bundles with data cord from the com system.
这样我们...
And then we...
我们兴许有逃出升天的机会
We may have a shot at getting out of here.
只剩一支了
There's only one left.
最好留着等你驾机  让我们脱离险境后再用
Better save it for when you fly us out of here.
我驾驶不了
I can't fly.
特别是打了吗啡后  我都头晕目眩的了
Especially all whacked up on morph.
这下可真他妈的好
Well, that's just frakking great.
他不会骗你的
He won't cheat.
他还是很诚实
He's too honorable.
不像你
Unlike you.
对  不像我
Yeah, unlike me.
我爱山姆  我恨山姆
I love Sam. I hate Sam.
我爱李  我恨李
I love Lee. I hate Lee.
天呐  我非得骗来骗去 才能保证不露马脚
Gods, I have to cheat just to keep the pieces all nice and neat.
打起精神
Stay with it.
你还得教我 怎么连接这些航空元件
You still gotta walk me through these avionics.
赛昂人已经到达神庙了 轮机长  你那边情况如何?
APOLLO: The Cylons have reached the Temple. Chief, what's your status?
我正在连接最后一个引爆器
I'm wiring the last detonator.
"朱庇特之眼" 一定就在这间神庙里的某个地方
D'ANNA: The Eye of Jupiter has to be somewhere in this Temple.
他们安上了炸药
CAVIL: They've wired it with explosives.
我们去拆下来
Let's disconnect it.
把引爆器拔出来 快
Pull out the detonators. Quickly.
轮机长  炸掉它!
APOLLO: Chief, blow this thing!
你他妈的疯了吗?
You out of your frakking mind?
我下不了手
I can't do it.
盖尤斯!        什么事?
Gaius! Yes?
来帮忙!
Help us!
好
Yeah.
把控制器给我
Give me the control!
这样就行了
This just about does it.
干!
Frak!
看你做的好事!  看你做的好事!
What have you done? What have you done?
少校  你看
Major, look.
那是什么东西?
What is that?
在那里  盖尤斯
There it is, Gaius.
你所有问题的答案就在那里
It has the answers to all of your questions.
那就是"朱庇特之眼"?
That's the Eye?
那是什么?
D'ANNA: What is?
哦 呃…
Oh, uh...
"混合体"曾说过...
Something the Hybrid said...
宝石蓝…
Sapphire blue
像一颗恒星一样发光
shining like unto a star.
戴・安娜
D'Anna...
你来这里不是为了寻找地球
You didn't come here looking for Earth.
而是别有用心
You came here looking for something else.
从中心星那里收到巨大能量脉冲
Picking up massive energy pulse from the central star.
长官 那是氦闪 那颗恒星要变成超新星了
Sir, it's a helium flash. The star's going nova.
超新星将在不到一个小时内 扫平整个星球
Nova's gonna obliterate the entire planet in less than an hour.
少校  看
Major, look.
那是神庙里的曼荼罗
It's the mandala from the Temple.
就应该是这样
This is supposed to be happening.
就是这样
That's it.
原来它一直近在眼前
I was staring at it the whole time.
那颗太阳要变成超新星了
The sun is going nova.
那颗超新星就是"朱庇特之眼"
The nova is the Eye of Jupiter.
好  我们还能炸掉它 我们去把它炸掉
All right, we can still blow it. We can still blow it.
只要能到轨道上就行 卡拉狄加会在那里找到我们 好吗?
We just gotta make it into orbit. Galactica will find us from there, okay?
好
Okay.
Good.
这是我的宿命
This is my destiny.
去见证是什么存在于生死之间
To see what lies between life and death.
还有去看"终极五人"的样子
And to look upon the faces of the Final Five.
不行
That can't happen.
这是我的宿命
This is my destiny.
对不起了  戴・安娜
Sorry, D'Anna.
"终极五人"
The Final Five.
真的是你们
Is it really you?
是你...
You.
原谅我的有眼无珠
Forgive me, I... I had no idea.
什么有眼无珠?
No idea about what?
你看到了什么?
What did you see? What...
是谁?
Who was it?
好美
So beautiful...
什么好美?
What was?
告诉我 我是你们中的一员吗?
Tell me! Am I one of you?
你说对了
You were right.
什么说对了?
About what?
戴・安娜 你看到我了吗?
D'Anna, did you see my face?
我必须得知道  求你了
I have to know, please.
求你了  振作  我必须得知道
Please, stay with me. Stay, I have to know!
告诉我!  我必须得知道!  你看到我了吗?
Tell me, I have to know! Did you see my face?
我是赛昂人吗?
Am I a Cylon?
妈的
Frak.
神啊  在我死前告诉我真相
God, tell me the truth before I die.
欢迎回家  总统阁下
Welcome home, Mr. President.
上将  赛昂舰队跳跃走了
Admiral, the Cylon fleet just jumped away.
他们不想被那颗超新星波及到
They don't wanna be here when that nova shock front gets here.
我们也不想
Neither do we.
立即展开营救行动
Launch a rescue mission, now.
超新星会把系统里的部件都烧掉 我们时间不多了
We don't have much time before the nova fries everything in the system.
与时间赛跑
It's gonna be a photo finish.
救援船清点完毕!
HOSHI: All rescue ships from the planet accounted for.
倒数计时!
Count us down!
启动超光速引擎    启动超光速引擎
Commence FTL. HOSHI: Commencing FTL.
三 二 一
GAETA: Jump in three, two, one...
我来吧
I got it.
他还没死?        可惜还没死
He's not dead? No, unfortunately.
关他禁闭
Take him to the brig.
莎伦
Sharon!
你好
Hi.
必须把她马上送到科特尔医生那里
We have to get her to Doc Cottle right away.
好吗    好的
Okay? Okay.
举枪!
Stick up!
别开枪  别开枪
Hold your fire! Hold your fire.
她帮我们逃出来的    让开!
She helped us escape. Get out of the way!
中尉
Lieutenant.
莎伦
Sharon...
轮机长说得对
I think the Chief is right.
那颗超新星确实像是神庙内的曼陀缴
I think the nova does look like the mandala inside of this Temple.
你说当时的第13部落 料到会发生什么事了吗?
Do you think the Thirteenth Tribe had a vision of what was to come?
我看不出它还代表什么?
I don't know what else it could mean.
可能他们那时也看到了一颗超新星  然后画了下来
Maybe they saw another nova, and drew a picture of that.
看过一颗超新星  其他的都一样
You've seen one nova, you've seen them all.
确实还有一颗超新星
Well, there was another nova.
4000年前在这里出现的  大约在神庙刚落成时
Seen 4,000 years ago, around about when the Temple might have been built.
距离我们当前位置有13000光年
It's 13,000 light years from our present position.
被称为爱奥尼亚星云的一团气体
It's a cloud of gas known as the lonian Nebula.
那可能就是...
Maybe it was a road sign
显示他们去向的路标
showing the direction that they headed to next.
星芭 像你一样
So, Starbuck, is that what you gotta do
就可以躺在床上多休息一会了吗?
to get a little actual rack time around here?
你来这里是和我扯皮的吗?
Did you just come by to frak with me?
我其实是来问你...
Actually, I wanted to know if you had any...
是否有以前 你在卡布里卡上的家的照片的
pictures of your old apartment on Caprica.
嗯
Um...
有哇
Yeah. Uh...
那个柜子最上层的雪茄盒里
The locker, top shelf. Cigar box.
为什么问我这事?
Why?
有些好奇
I'm curious about something.
但愿你和莎伦  不是打算要重新装修
Well, I hope you and Sharon aren't planning on redecorating,
因为从我原来的住处那里  你们可得不到任何灵感
'cause you're not gonna get any bright ideas from my old place.
这我记得
I remember.
我看火车失事后的残骸都比你那里强
I've seen better looking train wrecks.
过奖了
Thank you.
你还记得你作的那些画吗?
But I do remember those paintings you did.
那些画怎么了?
STARBUCK: What about them?
这是神庙里的图案
This was on the Temple.
你的画从哪里得来的灵感?
Where'd you get the idea to paint yours?
不知道
I don't know.
我从小就那么乱涂了
It was just something I've been doodling since I was a kid.
我喜欢那个图案
I liked the pattern.
呃…
Well...
他们在4000年前建造的神庙
They built the Temple 4,000 years ago.
怎么了?
What is it?
李・奥本有一次曾说过...
Just something Leoben said once.
我有我的宿命
That I had a destiny.
一切都已是命中注定
That it had already been written.
你知道规矩
You know the drill.
长吸一口气  匀速深呼吸
Long, deep, controlled breathing.
至少你不会再受这个苦了
At least you'll never have to go through this again.
做出这个决定并不容易 但这个结局是不可避免的
The decision wasn't easy, but the conclusion was inevitable.
你的型号有先天性的缺陷
Your model is fundamentally flawed.
不
No.
去寻问我们存在的意义 并不是一种缺陷
It's not a flaw to question our purpose.
不是吗?
Is it?
想知道是谁  为什么创造了我们  让我们拥有这样的思维方式
To wonder who programmed us, the way we think and why?
这恰恰就是问题所在
Well, that's the problem right there.
弥塞亚罪名是 你肩负特殊使命来指点我们
The messianic conviction that you're on a special mission to enlighten us.
看看它为我们所带来的危害
Look at the damage it's caused.
如果再给我一次机会我还会那么做的
I would do it all again.
恩  我们知道
Yes, we know.
所以我们已决定...
That's why we've decided to
把你的型号雪藏
box your entire line.
你的意识  记忆…  你这个型号所拥有的每个想法…
Your consciousness, memory, every thought your model ever had
都会被送入冷藏库
are going into cold storage.
无限期
Indefinitely.
欲知真相的人必死
One must die to know the truth.
还有五个赛昂人  兄弟
There are five other Cylons, Brother.
我看到他们了
I saw them.
总有一天 你也会看到的
One day, you're gonna see them, too.
总有一天
One day.
再见
Good-bye.
兄弟
Brother...